savethearctic.com 2012-12-22

# Privacy Policy | Greenpeace International

****The Greenpeace International website (referred to as 'website') is managed by Greenpeace International _(Stichting Greenpeace Council)_ (referred to as 'we') located at Ottho Heldringstraat 5, 1066 AZ Amsterdam, The Netherlands.

Stichting Greenpeace Council is considered the 'data controller' within the meaning of the applicable data protection legislation _(Wet bescherming persoonsgegevens)_. The Dutch data protection authority (College Bescherming Personnsgegevens) has been notified of the processing of personal data as undertaken by us and described in this document. 

**Information collection and processing purposes**

We ask you to provide your name and contact details when posting a comment, signing a petition, or making a donation on our website. We may also maintain records with details of individuals who contact us for (further) information or for help, but only in case we need to contact them later on or provide further information to them in the future.

If you like, you can register on our website by creating a website account. You then need to provide your name and contact details. By creating a website account, you avoid having to fill in your details every time you visit our website.

By providing your e-mail address, you can also subscribe to our [mailing list](http://www.greenpeace.org/international/en/My/sign-up/) in order to receive our email newsletter and urgent alerts.

We show social networking sharing buttons and widgets from Facebook, Google, Twitter and AddThis on our website to enable you to easily share Greenpeace campaigns and news with friends. These social networking sharing buttons and widgets come from web servers which may track your behaviour on our website and may combine this with other information about you originating from other websites. You can install a browser add-on like "Disconnect" for [Chrome](https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/jeoacafpbcihiomhlakheieifhpjdfeo?hc=search&hcp=main) and [Firefox](https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/user/6016894/) to disable them.

We also gather information automatically about website visitors to help us maintain and improve the design of our website. We use Google Analytics to gather this data and analyze it. You can install the "[Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)" to prevent information about your visits to our website being sent to Google Analytics.

**Information sharing and disclosure practices**

Your name may appear together with your comments on our website. To inspire others to take action, we may also show your name and a summary of what you have just done on our website for example, if you sign a petition or make a donation. If you petition someone using our website - for example a government official or company CEO - then we may send your name and email address with your message to them.

Registering by creating a website account on this website,  will also enable you to login on many national or regional Greenpeace websites, so that you can also place comments and take action on other Greenpeace websites without having to re-enter your contact details every time. This privacy policy will not apply to the national/regional Greenpeace websites which are managed by the national/regional Greenpeace offices themselves. You can find the privacy policy of each Greenpeace website by clicking on "Privacy Statement" or "Privacy Policy" in the local language in the footer of their homepage.

Greenpeace is active in over 40 countries, and your local office is probably best suited to keep you updated. Therefore if you subscribe to our mailing list on this website and there is a Greenpeace office in your country, we may share your contact details with them to provide you with the most suitable newsletter and urgent alerts. 

We may also disclose and provide access to the information you provided to our vendors and contractors who are performing services on our behalf.  However, such vendors and contractors are not permitted to use your information for any purpose other than providing services to us. Finally, where we pass your information on to vendors or contractors located in countries outside the European Economic Area, we will make sure that they apply the same level of protection to your information as we do. 

**Security measures**

We have implemented appropriate technical and organisational measures to secure personal data against loss or against any form of unlawful processing. Our donation pages are secured using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL), a security protocol that provides communications privacy over the Internet in a way that is designed to prevent eavesdropping, tampering, or message forgery.

Only employees who need to access information about supports and website visitors to perform their work are granted access to this personal identifiable information.

**Questions regarding the processing of your information and your rights**

Should you have any questions on the processing of your personal data or if you would like to know which personal data are processed, or you would like to alter, delete or block some of the information processed concerning you, please contact supporter services on: .

We are obliged to request proof of identity before access is given.

If you would like us to remove your information from our mailing list, please click the "Unsubscribe" link at the buttom of any email we sent to you or contact us at .

**Review of and questions regarding the privacy policy**

This privacy policy is reviewed on a regular basis. So please regularly check our website to find our latest version of the privacy policy.

If you have any questions relating to this policy, please address them to:

> Greenpeace International  
>  Ottho Heldringstraat 5  
>  1066 AZ Amsterdam  
>  The Netherlands  
>  Tel: +31 20 7182000   
>  Fax: +31 20 7182002   
>  or write to 

**Last updated: 14 June 2012**
